Inventory of the Anastasia Posadskaya Interviews
Hoover Institution Archives
Anastasia Posadskaya interviews
1994
98006
Posadskaya, Anastasia, interviewer
1 manuscript box, 1 oversize box (1.15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Sound recordings and transcripts of interviews of Russian women, relating to social conditions for women over the course of Soviet history. Used as the basis for the book edited by Barbara Alpern Engel and Anastasia Posadskaya, A Revolution of Their Own: Voices of Women in Soviet History (Boulder, Colo., 1998).
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1998.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Posadskaya was a visiting fellow at the Center for Russian, Central, and East European Studies at Rutgers University.
Scope and Content of Collection
Sound recordings and transcripts of interviews of Russian women, relating to social conditions for women over the course of Soviet history. Used as the basis for the book edited by Barbara Alpern Engel and Anastasia Posadskaya, A Revolution of Their Own: Voices of Women in Soviet History (Boulder, Colo., 1998). Some of the sound recordings do not have transcripts; there is also one transcript without a matching tape.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Women--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--Social conditions.; Phonotapes.; Engel, Barbara Alpern.
Collection Contents
- Transcripts, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Berezhnaia, Antonina Aleksandrovna, 1994 March 12 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Dolgikh, Elena Trofimovna, 1994 August 25 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Domracheva, Frida Frantzeva, 1994 March 9 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Dubova, Anna Akimovna, 1994 May 31 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Fleisher, Vera Konstantinovna, 1994 March 10 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Gilinskaia, Evgeniia Semenovna, no date (Folder 1: 6)
  - Kniazeva, Irina Ivanovna, 1994 August 25 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Malakhova, Vera Ivanovna, 1994 August 26 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Moskvina, Anna Aleksandrovna, 1994 August 26 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Nazmieva, Taskira Shegapovna, 1994 March 9 (Folder 1: 10)
  - Pavlova, Sofiia Nikandrovna, 1994 May 7 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Ponomarenko, Elena Grigor'evna, 1994 August 24 (Folder 1: 12)
- Sound Recordings of Interviews, 1994 (Box 2: 1)
  33 compact sound cassettes
  - Berezhnaia, Antonina Aleksandrovna, Ekaterinburg, 1994 March 12 (Folder 2)
  - Dolgikh, Elena Trofimovna, Tomsk, 1994 August 25 (Folder 2)
  - Domracheva, Frida Frantzevna, Zarechnyĭ, 1994 March 9 (Folder 2)
  - Dubova, Anna Akimovna, Moscow, 1994 May 31 (Folder 2)
  - Fleisher, Vera Konstantinovna, Zarechnyĭ, 1994 March 10 (Folder 2)
  - Gilinskaia, Evgeniia Semenovna, Moscow, 1994 (Folder 2)
  - Glazyrina, Olga Ivanovna, Ekaterinburg, 1994 (Folder 2)
  - Gorovaia, Mariia Mikhaĭlovna, Novozybkov, 1994 June 7 (Folder 2)
  - Gribacheva, Mariia Ivanovna, Novozybkov, Vnukovichi village, 1994 (Folder 2)
  - Kniazeva, Irina Ivanovna, Tomsk, 1994 August 25 (Folder 2)
  - Korniltzeva, Aleksandra Grigor'evna, Mezenki settlement, 1994 March 10 (Folder 2)
  - Makuleva, Valentina Kirillovna, 1994 (Folder 2)
  - Moskvina, Anna Aleksandrovna, Tomsk, 1994 August 26 (Folder 2)
  - Nazmieva, Taskira Shegapovna, Zarechnyĭ, 1994 March 9 (Folder 2)
  - Pashkova, Sofiia Iosifovna, 1994 (Folder 2)
  - Pavlova, Sofiia Nikandrovna, Moscow, 1994 May 7 (Folder 2)
  - Petrianina, Tatiana Ivanovna, Novozybkov, 1994 May 4 (Folder 2)
  - Plotnikova, Nina Nikolaevna, 1994 (Folder 2)
  - Ponomarenko, Elena Grigor'evna, Tomsk, 1994 August 24-27 (Folder 2)
  - Radosteva, Agniia Nikolaevna, Ekaterinburg, 1994 March 12 (Folder 2)
  - Solodovnikova, Aleksandra Ivanovna, Novozybkov, 1994 (Folder 2)